<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-1.0.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <title>Norconex Importer Project</title>
    <author email="info@norconex.com">Norconex Inc.</author>
  </properties>
  <body>

    <release version="2.7.0-SNAPSHOT" date="2017-??-??" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Added schema-based XML configuration validation which can be trigged
        on command prompt with this new flag: -checkcfg
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New MergeTagger for combining multiple fields into one.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        CharacterCaseTagger now support "swap" and "string" to swap 
        character case and capitalize beginning of a string, respectively.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: Apache Tika 1.14, Norconex Commons Lang 1.13.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Modified Javadoc to include an XML usage example for all 
        XML-configurable classes.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependent libraries for JPEG200 and JBIG2 image formats are no longer
        distributed with this product for licensing incompatibilities.
        To enable them, you will need JAR files found at these locations: 
        http://central.maven.org/maven2/com/github/jai-imageio/jai-imageio-jpeg2000/
        http://central.maven.org/maven2/com/levigo/jbig2/levigo-jbig2-imageio/
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="remove">
        Removed FixedHtmlEncodingDetector class in favor of the fixed version 
        of HtmlEncodingDetector. https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1837
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="remove">
        Removed deprecated Importer HTMLParser and PDFParser classes.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="remove">
        Removed deprecated IDocumentSplittableEmbeddedParser interface.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="remove">
        Removed Importer EnhancedPDFParser and EnhancedPDF2XHTML in favor of 
        upgraded TIKA PDFParser and PDF2XHTML versions.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.6.1" date="2016-12-14" description="Minor release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add" issue="39">
        DOMTagger now supports a new flags called "matchBlanks" to extract
        elements that contain empty values or values made of white spaces only. 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        ReplaceTagger now supports new flags: "wholeMatch" and "replaceAll".
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update" issue="39">
        The default value in DOMTagger can how be an empty string or a 
        string made of white spaces.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: Norconex Commons Lang 1.12.3, Joda Time 2.9.4, 
        Apache HTTP Client 4.5.2, Apache HTTP Core 4.4.5, JJ2000 5.3,
        JAI ImageIO jpeg2000 1.3.1
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix" issue="29">
        Fixed ReplaceTagger not adding replaced value to "toField" when it
        is the same as original value.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed NoSuchMethodError when performing OCR on some PDFs with JPEG 
        2000 images in them. 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed "No ImageWriter found for 'jpx' format" when performing OCR on 
        some PDFs with JPX images in them. 
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.6.0" date="2016-08-25" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CountMatchesTagger that will count occurrences of matching
        substring or regular expression in a field value or document content
        and store the count in a target field.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        DateFormatTagger now accepts multiple source formats when 
        attempting to convert dates, trying them in order provided.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add" issue="28">
        DOMTagger can now apply DOM selection on an optional "fromField" and
        can also use a "defaultValue" when there is no match.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DOM selector possibility for DOMContentFilter and DOMTagger:
        ownText, data, id, tagName, val, className, cssSelector, 
        and attr(attributeKey).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        TranslatorSplitter now supports Yandex translation service.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        GenericDocumentParserFactory/AbstractTikaParser now allows you to 
        control which embedded documents you do not want extracted from their 
        containers.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        GenericDocumentParserFactory/AbstractTikaParser now allows you to 
        control which documents containers you do not want to extract their 
        embedded documents.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        GenericDocumentParserFactory/AbstractTikaParser now allows you to 
        specify which content types to "split" their embedded documents 
        via regular expression.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        GenericDocumentParserFactory now allows you to define and configure
        parsers via XML.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New IHintsAwareParser interface for parsers that can benefit from
        global configuration settings.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New ParseHints class holding generic configuration settings to 
        be set on parsers implementing the new IHintsAwareParser.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New EmbeddedConfig class holding configuration settings related
        to embedded documents.  Used by ParseHints on 
        GenericDocumentParserFactory.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Can now pass optional -e or --contentEncoding to command line
        to explicitly set the character encoding (charset).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        LanguageTagger now uses Tika language detection (supports at least
        70 languages). 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        GenericDocumentParserFactory has been modified to introduce the 
        concept of ParseHints which holds configuration settings every
        parsers have the option to support or not. Generic embedded and OCR 
        configuration settings have been moved to the new ParseHints class.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        The following GenericDocumentParserFactory method are now deprecated:
        setSplitEmbedded(boolean), isSplitEmbedded(), setOCRConfig(OCRConfig),
        and getOCRConfig().
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        It is now possible to configure ExternalParser via XML.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Now validates configuration and variable file paths when launched on 
        the command line (throws errors on invalid paths).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: Tika 1.13 (which now uses PDFBox 2.x),
        Norconex Commons Lang 1.9.1, JSoup 1.9.2.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        OCRConfig#setContentTypes(String) and equivalent configuration option
        in GenericDocumentParserFactory now expects a regular expression as
        opposed to a coma-separated list of content types.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        DebugTagger now assumes UTF-8 instead of OS default charset when 
        printing content.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Subclasses of AbstractStringTagger will now see tagTextDocument(...)
        method invoked at least once even if there is no content supplied.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix" issue="21">
        Fixed DOMTagger ignoring subsequent selectors when one selector 
        has no match. 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed ContentTypeDetector not closing TikaInputStream properly resulting
        in temporary "apache-tika-XXX.tmp" files not being deleted properly.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed infinite loop with DOMSplitter when some selectors are too 
        generic.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        AbstractCharStreamTagger now tolerates null content stream.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.5.2" date="2016-05-31" description="Maintenance release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        It is now possible to specify a locale when parsing/formatting dates
        with CurrentDateTagger and DateFormatTagger.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: PDFBox 2.0.0 (final release).
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.5.1" date="2016-03-22" description="Bug fix release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Text-based transformers extending AbstractCharStreamTransformer now 
        logs a warning when character encoding could not be detected,
        suggesting to make sure the content being transformed is text.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        StripBetweenTransformer now accepts multiple strip endpoints with
        the same "start" regex.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.5.0" date="2016-02-28" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        DOMTagger and DOMFilter can now be told how to return matching elements 
        values (i.e., text, html, or outerHtml).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CharsetTagger to convert the character encoding of specified
        document metadata field into the desired target character encoding.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CharsetTransformer to convert the character encoding of a 
        document content into the desired target character encoding.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CharsetUtil class offering simplified charset detection and 
        conversion methods.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        The "log4j.properties" file has been moved from classes to the 
        installation root directory.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        DOMTagger now returns matching element text as opposed to HTML
        (can be configured back to HTML).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        When used as pre-parse handlers, most handlers dealing with text 
        now accepts a charset to use for parsing content, or will detect 
        encoding when no charset is specified.  This eliminates many 
        bad character issues.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Metadata document.contentEncoding is now always set when passed 
        to importDocument method.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: Apache Tika 1.12, Norconex Commons Lang 1.9.0.
        Jempbox 1.8.11 (still required by Tika JPegParser), PDFBox 2.0.0-RC3,
        Apache Commons CLI 1.3.1.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Importer-specific version of Tika PDFParser was updated to work around
        PDFBox 2.0 no longer depending on Jempbox.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Importer now issues a WARN instead of DEBUG sometimes thrown
        when importing fails.
      </action>
      <action dev="tballison" type="fix">
        Fixed invalid zip bomb detection on PDF with elements nested more
        than 100 level deep.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed charset in HTML comments being wrongfully considered when
        charset is being detected.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed NullPointerException being thrown with some PDFs when extracting
        multilingual items.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.4.0" date="2015-11-02" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        The following new handlers enable using scripting languages to define
        processing logic: ScriptFilter, ScriptTagger, and ScriptTransformer.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add" issue="48">
        New DOMContentFilter to filter out XML/HTML documents containing
        identified element or element value using a friendly syntax
        to navigate a DOM-tree structure.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DOMSplitter handler to split XML/HTML documents into multiple 
        documents based on a specified element.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DOMTagger handler to extract text elements from XML/HTML 
        documents using a friendly syntax to navigate a DOM-tree structure. 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        CharacterCaseTagger can now be applied to field names
        (in addition to, or instead of, values).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CommonRestrictions class to obtain restrictions commonly associated
        with certain documents.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New methods on AbstractImporterHandler to deal with restrictions:
        #addRestriction(PropertyMatcher...), 
        #addRestrictions(List&lt;PropertyMatcher&gt;)
        #removeRestriction(String), #getRestrictions()
        #removeRestriction(PropertyMatcher), #clearRestrictions()
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        New file formats supported (brought by Tika update):
        GCMD DIF, Geographic ISO 19139 files, CBOR. 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: Apache Tika 1.10, JSoup 1.8.3, 
        Norconex Commons Lang 1.8.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Importer ExternalParser now uses corrected ExternalParser from Tika.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        AbstractStringTransformer#transformStringContent(...) now throws
        an ImporterHandlerException.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Saved and loaded configuration-related classes are now equal.
        Methods equals/hashCode/toString for those classes are now implemented
        uniformly and where added where missing.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed some configuration classes not always being saved to XML 
        properly or giving errors.
      </action>      
    </release>

    <release version="2.3.1" date="2015-08-07" description="Maintenance release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Dependency updates: Norconex Commons Lang 1.7.0.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.3.0" date="2015-07-21" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New TextPatternTagger for extracting text matching regular expressions
        out of a document content and storing matches into a field.
        New unit tests created for it.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Jar manifest now includes implementation entries and 
        specifications entries (matching Maven pom.xml).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Javadoc fixes and updates.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Library updates: Norconex Commons Lang 1.6.2.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed NullPointerException in DebugTagger when a field contains a null
        value.
      </action>
    </release>
  
    <release version="2.2.0" date="2015-06-15" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DocumentLengthTagger for adding the document byte length 
        as a field to imported documents.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CurrentDateTagger for adding the current date as a field to 
        imported documents.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New NumericMetadataFilter for filtering documents based on whether a
        numeric field value matches a given numeric range.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DateMetadataFilter for filtering documents based on whether a
        date field value matches a given date range.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New ExternalParser class which is used to run an external process
        for parsing files (e.g. pdftotext) of the associated content type.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        By default PDF parsing is now done with this flag set to true:
        "suppressDuplicateOverlappingText". This should eliminate the 
        extraction of duplicate text in PDF where bolding is done by
        having multiple instance of the same string on top of each other.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update" issue="9">
        Complete rewrite of AbstractStringFilter, AbstractStringTagger, 
        and AbstractStringTransformer to limit the memory taken for
        loading the content. Now the memory is specified in absolute terms
        instead of dynamically allocating it based on free memory 
        (an approach that could cause OutOfMemory errors). All subclasses
        now accept a "maxReadSize" configuration option to set the 
        maximum number of characters to process at once.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        The abstract methods accepting a "partial" boolean argument 
        on AbstractStringFilter, AbstractStringTagger, 
        and AbstractStringTransformer have been changed to now accept
        a "sectionIndex" integer, representing the document content section
        being processed. Only larger documents will be processed one section
        of text at a time (to preserve memory).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        AbstractCharStreamTransformer#transformTextDocument(...) now 
        throws an ImporterHandlerException instead of IOException to be
        consistent with other handlers.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        TitleGeneratorTagger was re-written no longer uses Carrot, to 
        reduce library dependencies.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Removed custom Tika mappings for Microsoft Visio now that they have 
        been added to default Tika mappings in Tika 1.8.
        Reference: https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1286
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        ReplaceTagger: now case insensitive by default. Added a new
        flag to turn case-sensitivity on/off. #addReplacement(...) methods
        have been deprecated in favor of addReplacement(Replacement).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Regular expressions in RegexContentFilter, RegexMetadataFilter, 
        ReplaceTagger, TextBetweenTagger, ReplaceTransformer, 
        StripAfterTransformer, StripBeforeTransformer, and 
        StripBetweenTransformer now always have the
        Pattern.DOTALL flags enabled and when case
        sensitivity is enabled for regex, Pattern.UNICODE_CASE is now always
        used.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Library updates: Apache Tika 1.8, Norconex Commons Lang 1.6.1,
        Apache Commons CLI 1.3, Apache Jempbox 1.8.9, Jempbox 2.0.0.
        Removed these library "direct" dependencies: Carrot2 (3.9.4), 
        Lucene Analyzers (5.0.0), and Stax2 API (3.1.4).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Javadoc fixes and updates.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        New unit tests to cover all filter onMatch use cases.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed filters not working properly when using 
        onMatch="include". Affects all subclasses of AbstractDocumentFilter,
        which now details the include/exclude logic in its Javadoc
        (github collector-http#108).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed "Too many open files" exception.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix" issue="7">
        Fixed the "restrictTo" feature not always working for 
        AbstractImporterHandler subclasses.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.1.1" date="2015-04-08" description="Maintenance release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        PDFBox now uses latest snapshot (as opposed to a frozen one).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Javadoc fixes.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Library updates: SLF4J 1.7.12.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.1.0" date="2015-03-31" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Added OCR support using Tesseract open-source product. Configured
        by setting an OCRConfig to GenericDocumentParserFactory.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Added document translation support with the new TranslatorSplitter.
        Support these translation APIs: Microsoft, Google, Lingo24, and Moses.
        Both the document content and/or chosen fields can be translated.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New TitleGeneratorTagger to dynamically generate titles out of 
        documents, using Carrot2 to extract the best terms.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New EnhancedPDFParser and EnhancedPDF2XHTML classes modifying original 
        Tika PDFParser to add support for PDF XFA (dynamic forms) text 
        extraction as well as adding support for PDFBox 2.0.0 (which fixes 
        the striping of space characters between words in many PDFs).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New XFDLParser for parsing PureEdge Extensible Forms Description 
        Language files (XFDL). Supports both Gzipped+Base64 and plain text
        versions.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New WordPerfectParser class for parsing WordPerfect documents
        according to WordPerfect file specifications.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New QuattroProParser class for parsing QuattroPro documents
        according to QuattroPro file specifications.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New configuration "parseErrorsSaveDir" on importer configuration
        for saving files that caused parsing errors along with their exception
        and metadata if any.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        KeepOnlyTagger and DeleteTagger now supports regular expression for 
        identifying fields to keep/delete.  The field="" attribute has
        been replaced by a &lt;field&gt; element.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Added support for JBIG2 and jpeg2000 image formats.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Improved content detection of MS Office and Corel Office documents
        when importing an input stream with no specified extension.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Improved overall content detection accuracy and performance.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Default allocated memory for caching of document content was increased
        by a factor of 10 (10MB max per document, 100MB max total).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        AbstractTikaParser can now be extended to modify Tika ParseContext.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        importer.bat and importer.sh will now load the log4j.properties 
        from the ./classes folder.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Now always flush output stream from parsers so implementors do not 
        have to be concerned with this.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Easier to extend GenericDocumentParserFactory to provide custom
        parsers. Dropped "registerNamedParser", "registerFallbackParser",
        and "getFallbackParser" methods in favor of new "createFallbackParser"
        and "createNamedParsers" methods.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        HTMLParser and PDFParser are now deprecated. HTML and PDF are now 
        handled by the fall-back parser (auto-detected).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        IDocumentSplittableEmbeddedParser is now deprecated and has no effect.
        Will be deleted in a future release.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Minor javadoc improvements and fixes.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        No longer adds null handlers (possible when configuration loading 
        failed for an handler).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Improved exception handling for configuration loading.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Library updates: Tika 1.7, Norconex Commons Lang 1.6.0, JUnit 4.12,
        PDFBox 2.0.0 (SNAPSHOT-2015-03-28), Apache Commons Codec 1.10,
        Lucene Analyzer Common 5.0.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Updated several maven plugins and added SonarQube maven plugin.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Added Sonatype repository to pom.xml for snapshot releases.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Added more unit tests for various content type parsing.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed embedded objects not always having the right content-type.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed invalid mapping between "application/wordperfect" content type
        and WordPerfectParser.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed AbstractCharStreamTagger subclasses badly detecting character
        encoding and failing documents as a consequence.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="2.0.0" date="2014-11-25" description="Major release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Importing now returns an ImporterResponse, which may hold the imported
        document, along with nested documents, and and ImporterStatus.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New IDocumentSplitter handler and related classes, allowing 
        implementations to split documents into more documents.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        DefaultDocumentParserFactory can now be configured to treat embedded 
        documents as distinct documents (committed separately).  
        Parsers can now implement IDocumentSplittableEmbeddedParser to 
        indicate they are supporting document splitting. 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        DefaultDocumentParserFactory can now ignore parsing specified 
        content-types.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New IImporterResponseProcessor to process the import response.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Document encoding can now be explicitly specified when importing and 
        the value get stored as a metadata field.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New ContentTypeDetector for detecting the content-type from documents.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New ImporterDocument, holding all objects related to a document being
        imported.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New ImporterMetadata, extending Properties to provide additional
        import-related convenience methods and constants.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CsvSplitter class for splitting coma-separated value files into
        multiple records/documents to be indexed.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New RegexContentFilter for accepting/rejecting documents based
        on a successful regular expression match on their content.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CharacterCaseTagger for modifying the character case of a metadata 
        field value.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DateFormatTagger for parsing/formatting date from specified
        metadata fields.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New DebugTagger for logging document content and/or metadata to 
        help with implementation and troubleshooting.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New LanguageTagger which analyzes a document content to automatically
        detect and store as metadata the document language.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New TextStatisticsTagger that stores as metadata statistical information
        about a document content (word count, average words per sentences, 
        etc.).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New AbstractDocument* class for each types of handlers, facilitating
        handler implementation.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Directory where temporary files are created is now configurable.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Added support for parsing .iso files.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Now licensed under The Apache License, Version 2.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Document content reads and writes are now performed in memory up to 
        a configurable maximum size, after which the filesystem gets used.
        This reduces I/O and improves performance.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Now every handlers except filters can be restricted to matching
        metadata values (configurable).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        *.tagger, *.filter, and *.transformer handlers were move to 
        *.handler.tagger, *.handler.filter, and *.handler.transformer.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        com.norconex.importer.ContentType has been replaced with 
        com.norconex.commons.lang.file.ContentType.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        For consistency, several references to metadata field names were 
        renamed to use the term "field" (instead of property or else). 
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        DefaultDocumentParserFactory was renamed to 
        GenericDocumentParserFactory.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="remove">
        Handler "contentTypeRegex" tag was removed from handlers that 
        supported it in favor of the more flexible "restrictTo" tag(s).
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.3.0" date="2014-08-18" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Now stores the content "family" for each documents as 
        "importer.contentFamily".  This is a higher level representation
        of a file content types.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New SplitTagger: Split values into multiple-values using a separator
        of choice.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New CopyTagger: copies document metadata fields to other fields.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New HierarchyTagger: splits a field string into multiple segments 
        representing each node of a hierarchical branch.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Improved detection of certain mime types, such as those previously 
        appearing as application/x-tika-*.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        ReplaceTagger now supports regular expressions (via a new "regex" flag).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Can now detect these MS Viso mime-types properly: vsdx, vstc, vssx, 
        vsdm, vstm, vssm.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        AbstractCharStreamTransformer now enforces streaming as UTF8.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Now requires Java 7 or higher.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        RelpaceTagger regular matching now only replaces matching "fromValue".
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.2.0" date="2014-03-09" description="Feature release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Now extracts text from WordPerfect documents 
        (new WordPerfectParser class).
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New transformer "ReduceConsecutivesTransformer" to reduce consecutive
        instances of the same string to only one instance.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New transformer "ReplaceTransformer" to perform search and replace
        on document content using regular expression.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New filter "EmptyMetadataFilter" to exclude/include documents with
        no data for one or more specified metadata properties.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Library updates: Tika 1.5, Norconex Commons Lang 1.3.0.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Now attempts to detect the character encoding from a character stream
        by looking at a Content-Type metadata.  If none is present, defaults
        to UTF-8.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="fix">
        Fixed NPE in AbstractTextRestrictiveHandler when
        no content-type is found when used before parsing.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2013-08-20" description="Minor release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New tagger "TextBetweenTagger" to extract strings from a document
        and store them into document meta data fields.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New AbstractRestrictiveHandler and AbstractTextRestrictiveHandler
        abstract classes to facilitate re-use of common capabilities in 
        handlers.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        New BufferUtil and Memory Util classes.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        AbstractRestrictiveTransformer now deprecated.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Upgraded norconex-commons-lang to 1.1.0.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.1" date="2013-08-02" description="Maintenance release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Upgraded Apache Tika from 1.3 to 1.4.
      </action>
      <action dev="essiembre" type="update">
        Removed dependency on aspectjrt due to GPL licencing incompatibility.
        If you need .iso parsing, you can manually download and add to the
        classpath.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2013-06-04" description="Open Source release">
      <action dev="essiembre" type="add">
        Starting with this release, Norconex Importer is open-source under GPL.
      </action>
    </release>

  </body>
</document>